Mss.SMs.Coll.13
American Philosophical Society
Anathan-Jacobs Grand Trunk Pacific Railway Collection
1905-1910
Mss.SMs.Coll.13
American Philosophical Society
1.0 ln. ft. 2 boxes.
Norman Leonard Jacobs was an engineer and surveyor with the Grand Trunk Pacific Railway in Canada. The collection consists of his correspondence with Bessie Frank (later Anathan), an acquaintance from Pittsburgh. Jacobs wrote of daily life in Canadian cities, interactions with First Nations tribes, and daily hardships encountered in the field (extreme cold, snowblindness, and lack of food), but also spoke of his work with pride and enthusiasm. In addition to the letters, Jacobs wrote twenty-eight pages of a "Diary of a Tenderfoot." Also included in the collection are two photobooks and various loose photographs, which display various aspects of camp life, details of work sites and landscape, as well as First Nations families, camps, and modes of transportation.
Jacobs, Norman Leonard, 1885-
Scope and Contents note
Series I includes 34 letters written to Bessie Frank (later Anathan) between 1905 and 1910. Letters written from Winnipeg offer Jacobs's positive impressions of the city and detail daily life (including employment in the book department of Eaton's, prior to work on the railroad). The majority of letters are written from Edmonton and various camps in the field. They provide details about camp life and the hardships faced by the surveyors: extreme cold, snowblindness, and lack of food. Two 1910 letters are posted from London; Jacobs finds the city crowded and unfriendly, and expresses pleasure at his anticipated return to Pittsburgh. The 28-page "Diary of a Tenderfoot," probably written in 1906, describes rail travel to Toronto, impressions of Winnipeg, and work in the field.
Series II includes a number of photographs, most organized in two photobooks. The majority of the photographs were taken in the field and depict various aspects of camp life and the Canadian landscape. There are also numerous images of First Peoples: portraits, family groups, camps, and means of transport.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Accession M2009-01. Donated by Ellen Lehman.
Biographical/Historical note
Norman Leonard Jacobs was born in Bath, England in 1885, the eldest child of Isaiah Woolf and Josephine (née Hast) Jacobs. His maternal grandfather, Marcus Hast, was the Chazan of the Great Synagogue in London and a collector and composer of music ( Avodat HaKodesh, 1910). Isaiah worked as the partner in a London accounting firm until its 1899 bankruptcy, after which he was employed in family businesses in London, Pittsburgh, and Detroit. One of Norman’s sisters, Ruth, married a Winnipeg barrister; after his early death, she supported herself and her son as a writer, gaining a large readership for articles and poetry written as “Sheila Rand” and “Wilhelmina Stitch.” Another, Dorothea, settled in Milwaukee, Wisconsin and raised a family.
Norman Jacobs moved to Pittsburgh in 1903 and spent two years working at his uncle Abraham’s insurance company, Benswanger & Hast. In 1905, he moved to Winnipeg, which he described with great enthusiasm and affection. He worked in the book department of Eaton’s Department Store for a few months, until he secured a position as a draughtsman in the engineering department of the Canadian Northern Railway. By April 1906 he was in the employ of the Grand Trunk Pacific and entered the field for the first time as a topographer. The survey teams were tasked with mapping routes that provided a four-tenths of one percent grade between the 50th and 55th parallel; by laying rail on such nearly level ground, the company aimed to travel through the Rocky Mountains as quickly as over prairies. Over the course of four years, Jacobs was employed in a variety of roles—leveler’s rodman, topographer’s rodman, quartermaster, topographer, leveler, head of a topographical and exploratory party, transit man, instrument man and draughtsman.
It was during his time with the Grand Trunk Pacific that he wrote most of the letters in the collection. The letters are to Bessie Frank (later Anathan), an acquaintance from Pittsburgh. The letters describe his life, the harsh conditions confronting the survey teams, as well as his impressions of life in Canada.
The Grand Trunk Pacific Railway, incorporated in 1903, was built between 1906 and 1914. Its 3000 miles of track extended from Winnipeg, Manitoba to Prince Rupert, British Columbia. The GTPR was a subsidiary of the Grand Trunk Railway, created in the hope that the transcontinental leg would help the GTR compete with the western track systems of the Canadian Pacific Railway and the Canadian Northern Railway. However, financial difficulties plagued the GTPR, and in 1919 the GTR was nationalized. Four years later, it was placed under the management of the Canadian National Railway.
Following the end of his survey work, Jacobs temporarily relocated to London, and in 1910 was engaged in post graduate schooling at the Imperial College of Science and Technology in London. In 1911, Jacobs returned to Pittsburgh and proposed marriage to Bessie Frank; she declined. In September of the same year, he became engaged to Flora Baer, a former Pittsburgher and resident of Philadelphia’s Germantown neighborhood. The proposal to Baer seems to have been hasty, for shortly thereafter Norman departed for Canada once more. He became a partner in Nordquist Bros., a railroad contractor; legal action was brought against the firm in 1912 and 1913. After this, the record is silent as to Norman Jacobs' fate.
Bibliography:
“Bankrupts from the London Gazette.” The Edinburgh Gazette. April 4, 1899. http://www.edinburgh-gazette.co.uk/issues/11081/pages/343/page.pdf. Accessed 3 November 2011.
Currey, Josiah Seymour. “Sidney M. Siesel.” In History of Milwaukee, City and County, Volume 2, 720. Chicago and Milwaukee: The S. J. Clarke Publishing Company, 1922. http://books.google.com/books/about/History_of_Milwaukee_city_and_county.html?id=0EEVAAAAYAAJ. Accessed 3 November 2011.
Goldsborough, Gordon. “Ruth Jacobs Cohen Collie (1888-1936).” The Manitoba Historical Society Website. http://www.mhs.mb.ca/docs/people/collie_rjc.shtml. Accessed 3 November 2011.
Lefkowitz, Sarah and Minnie Susman. “Bessie Frank Anathan Interview.” National Council of Jewish Women Oral History Project. March 4, 1975. AIS.1964.40. http://images.library.pitt.edu/cgi-bin/i/image/image-idx?view=entry;cc=ncjw;entryid=x-ais196440.015. Accessed 24 October 2011.
“McInnes v. Nordquist.” In The Manitoba Reports Vol. 23, edited by George Patterson, K.C., 815-22. Winnipeg: Stovel Company, Limited, 1913. http://books.google.com/ebooks/reader?id=XywvAAAAIAAJ&printsec=frontcover&output=reader. Accessed 3 November 2011.
Marsh, James. “Grand Trunk Railway of Canada.” The Canadian Encyclopedia. http://www.thecanadianencyclopedia.com/index.cfm?PgNm=TCE&Params=A1ARTA0003380. Accessed 10 November 2011.
Regehr, T. D. “Grand Trunk Pacific Railway.” The Canadian Encyclopedia. http://www.thecanadianencyclopedia.com/index.cfm?PgNm=TCE&Params=a1ARTA0003379. Accessed 10 November 2011.
Shisler, Geoffery L. The Homepage of Rabbi Geoffrey L. Shisler. http://geoffreyshisler.com/Hast.htm. Accessed 3 November 2011.
“Social and Local News.” The Jewish Criterion vol. 33, issue 4. September 1, 1911. http://pjn.library.cmu.edu/books/pages.cgi?call=CRI_1911_033_004_09011911&layout=vol0/part0/copy0&file=0010. Accessed 3 November 2011.
Talbot, Frederick A. The Making of a Great Canadian Railway. London: Seeley, Service & Co., Ltd., 1912. http://www.archive.org/details/makingofgreatcan00talb. Accessed 10 November 2011.
Anathan, Bessie Frank, 1885-1976 -- Correspondence; Anecdotes.; Diaries.; Dog teams--Canada--1890-1920.; Edmonton (Alta.)--History--20th century.; Frontier and pioneer life -- Canada.; Jews--Pennsylvania--Pittsburgh.; Native American Materials; Photographs.; Railroads--1900-1910.; Railroads--Canada.; Railroads--England.; Winnipeg (Man.)--History--20th century.; Winnipeg (Man.)--Social life and customs--20th century.
- Series I. Correspondence, 1906-undated; 0.5 ln. ft. 1 box.
  - Letter to Bessie Frank Anathan ("Dear Old Girl"), 1905 Nov. 22; 1.0 item; 8 pages. 6-3/4 x 9, folded.; Jacobs, Norman Leonard, 1885-
    Scope and Contents note
    Winnipeg. Wednesday 22nd. Likes and describes Manitoba.
    Earliest of the letters, based on content; Nov. 22 fell on a Wednesday in 1905.
    Anathan, Bessie Frank, 1885-1976 -- Correspondence; Anecdotes.; Winnipeg (Man.)--Social life and customs--20th century.
  - Letter to Bessie Frank Anathan ("Dear Old Girl"), 1905 Dec. 3, 5; 1.0 item; 12 pages. 8 x 10, folded.; Jacobs, Norman Leonard, 1885-
    Sunday and Tuesday, Winnipeg. Too late for a civil engineer position, may be sent out at Christmas. Hired at book department at Eaton's store, meeting "splendid fellows."
  - Letter to Bessie Frank Anathan ("Sister Mine"), 1905; 1.0 item; 10 pages. 6-3/4 x 10-1/4, folded (two sheets), 8-1/4 x 13.; Jacobs, Norman Leonard, 1885-
    Winnipeg. Speaks of his sister's engagement (Ruth's, not Dorothea's). "I haven't spoken of the Indians for the rather peculiar reason that they give one no first impressions." Excitement at receiving a letter from the Commissioners of the Transcontinental Railway in Ottawa, asking that he submit his maps and sketches, hopes that he may win an engineering position, for which he has developed great enthusiasm. No prospects at Benswanger & Hast (maternal uncle's insurance firm) "even suposing that I asked to be taken back which I won't."
    Late 1905 or early 1906, based on employment.
    Anathan, Bessie Frank, 1885-1976 -- Correspondence; Collie, Ruth, 1888-1936; Indians of North America--Canada.
  - Letter to Bessie Frank Anathan ("My Dear Girl"), 1906 Jan. 15; 1.0 item; 5 pages. 8 x 10-1/4, folded.; Jacobs, Norman Leonard, 1885-
    Winnipeg. Discusses books, cultural life, Winnipeg upper crust. Left Eaton's for railroad "Glory."
  - Letter to Bessie Frank Anathan ("Dear Bess"), 1906 Feb. 24; 1.0 item; 8 pages. 8 x 10-14, folded.; Jacobs, Norman Leonard, 1885-
    Winnipeg.
    Dated 1905, but likely 1906 based upon contents.
    Anathan, Bessie Frank, 1885-1976 -- Correspondence; Frontier and pioneer life -- Canada.; Indians of North America--Canada.
  - Letter to Bessie Frank Anathan ("My Ownest Sister"), 1906 Feb. 27; 1.0 item; 4 pages. 8 x 10-1/4, folded.; Jacobs, Norman Leonard, 1885-
    Anathan, Bessie Frank, 1885-1976 -- Correspondence; Jews--Pennsylvania--Pittsburgh.
  - Letter to Bessie Frank Anathan ("Dear Bettsy"), 1906 Mar. 24; 1.0 item; 8 pages. 6-3/4 x 10-1/4, folded.; Jacobs, Norman Leonard, 1885-
    Winnipeg. Regarding literary club.
    Anathan, Bessie Frank, 1885-1976 -- Correspondence; Indians of North America--Material culture--Canada.
  - Letter to Bessie Frank Anathan ("Dear Sis"), 1906 Apr. 2; 1.0 item; 3 pages. 6-3/4 x 10-1/4, folded.; Jacobs, Norman Leonard, 1885-
    Winnipeg. Regarding Indian "curios."
    Anathan, Bessie Frank, 1885-1976 -- Correspondence; Railroads--Canada.
  - Letter to Bessie Frank Anathan ("Dear Bess"), 1906 Apr. 18; 1.0 item; 2 pages. 7 x 8-3/4, folded.; Jacobs, Norman Leonard, 1885-
    Will be heading west on Thursday (by rail to the end of the line in Saskatchewan, then work toward the Rockies). News received shortly after posting an earlier letter.
    1906 based upon from 1906 Apr. 21 letter.
  - Letter to Bessie Frank Anathan ("Dear Bess"), 1906 Apr. 21; 1.0 item; 9 pages. 5 x 8.; Jacobs, Norman Leonard, 1885-
    Saturday the 21st. Base camp.
    1906 based upon 21st falling on Saturday.
  - Letter to Bessie Frank Anathan ("Dear Bettsy"), 1906 May 27; 1.0 item; 16 pages. 8-1/4 x 10-3/4, folded.; Jacobs, Norman Leonard, 1885-
    North West Territory. Letter from the field.
    1906 based on the recent change of employer (Grand Trunk Pacific rather than Canadian Northern), emphasized for the purpose of mail delivery.
    Anathan, Bessie Frank, 1885-1976 -- Correspondence; Frontier and pioneer life -- Canada.; Indians of North America--Canada.; Jews--Pennsylvania--Pittsburgh.; Railroads--Canada.
  - Letter to Bessie Frank Anathan ("Dear Bess"), 1906 Jul. 11; 1.0 item; 8 pages. 8 x 10.; Jacobs, Norman Leonard, 1885-
    In the field.
    Anathan, Bessie Frank, 1885-1976 -- Correspondence; Indians of North America--Material culture--Canada.; Railroads--Canada.
  - Letter to Bessie Frank Anathan ("Dear Bettsie"), 1906 Aug. 18; 1.0 item; 8 pages. 5-1/2 x 8-3/4.; Jacobs, Norman Leonard, 1885-
    North West Territory. In the field, 55th Lat.
  - Letter to Bessie Frank Anathan ("Dear Girlie"), 1906 Sep. 6; 1.0 item; 3 pages. 8 x 10-1/4.; Jacobs, Norman Leonard, 1885-
    In camp. Torchwood Hills, Northern Saskatchewan.
  - Letter to Bessie Frank Anathan ("Dear Sis"), 1906 Oct. 12; 1.0 item; 4 pages. 6-1/2 x 10-3/4.; Jacobs, Norman Leonard, 1885-
    Torchwood Hills. Incomplete.
  - Letter to Bessie Frank Anathan, 1906 Oct. 14; 1.0 item; 1 page. 5-1/2 x 8-3/4.; Jacobs, Norman Leonard, 1885-
    Dated, but no salutation; may be a fragment. Exhortation to " keep your hands warm."
  - Letter to Bessie Frank Anathan ("Dear Bess"), 1906 Nov. 16; 1.0 item; 7 pages. 8 x 10-1/4.; Jacobs, Norman Leonard, 1885-
    Torchwood Hills, Saskatchewan. Provides a Winnipeg address for reply.
    Anathan, Bessie Frank, 1885-1976 -- Correspondence; Canada--Religious life and customs.; Jews--Pennsylvania--Pittsburgh.; Railroads--Canada.
  - Letter to Bessie Frank Anathan ("Dear Bess"), 1906 Dec. 23; 1.0 item; 4 pages. 6 x 9-3/4, folded.; Jacobs, Norman Leonard, 1885-
  - Letter to Bessie Frank Anathan ("Dear Bess"), 1906 Dec. 30; 1.0 item; 4 pages. 6 x 9-1/2, folded.; Jacobs, Norman Leonard, 1885-
    T.C.R. Feeling in the dumps, but cheered by the camp and the outdoors.
    Anathan, Bessie Frank, 1885-1976 -- Correspondence; Dog teams--Canada--1890-1920.; Railroads--Canada.
  - Letter to Bessie Frank Anathan ("Dear Old Bess"), 1907 Dec. 26; 1.0 item; 6 pages. 8 x 10-3/4. Grand Trunk Pacific Railway Engineering Dept. letterhead.; Jacobs, Norman Leonard, 1885-
    Edmonton. Happy in his work, taking to surveying like "a duck to water" but not sure it's worthwhile; has responsibilities and is well-liked.
  - Letter to Bessie Frank Anathan ("Dear Sis"), 1907; 1.0 item; 1 page. 8 x 10-1/4. Upper right-hand corner of the page torn off.; Jacobs, Norman Leonard, 1885-
    In the field, between Lake Hepigon and the Sturgeon River. Suffering from snowblindness, cold, tough conditions, but well. "P.S. This letter goes in by Indian--hope he'll make it."
    Date based on 1907 Dec 26 and 1908 Mar 17 references to his eyes.
  - Letter to Bessie Frank Anathan ("Dear Old Chum"), 1908 Jan. 22; 1.0 item; 4 pages. 8 x 10-3/4. Grand Trunk Pacific Railway Engineering Dept. letterhead.; Jacobs, Norman Leonard, 1885-
    Edmonton. "Haven't married the biscuit shooter yet--her feet are too large" and description of his ideal "fair maiden."
  - Letter to Bessie Frank Anathan ("Dear Sister"), 1908 Feb. 14; 1.0 item; 5 pages. 8 x 10-3/4. Grand Trunk Pacific Railway Engineering Dept. letterhead.; Jacobs, Norman Leonard, 1885-
    In the field, 35 miles west of Edmonton. Description of terrain, difficult work.
  - Letter to Bessie Frank Anathan ("My Dear Sister"), 1908 Mar. 17; 1.0 item; 2 pages. 8 x 10-3/4. Grand Trunk Pacific Railway Engineering Dept. letterhead.; Jacobs, Norman Leonard, 1885-
    McLeod River, Alberta.
  - Letter to Bessie Frank Anathan ("Dear Bess"), 1908 May 1; 1.0 item; 5 pages. 8 x 10.; Jacobs, Norman Leonard, 1885-
    Edmonton.
    Anathan, Bessie Frank, 1885-1976 -- Correspondence; Edmonton (Alta.)--History--20th century.; Railroads--Canada.
  - Letter to Bessie Frank Anathan ("Dear Little Sister"), 1908 Jun. 8; 1.0 item; 4 pages. 8 x 10-1/4.; Jacobs, Norman Leonard, 1885-
    Rainy season, supply problems in western camps; no money to pay men or ability to feed them. Impressions of "Western Girls" and sadness at disappearing "Habitants."
    Anathan, Bessie Frank, 1885-1976 -- Correspondence; Frontier and pioneer life -- Canada.; Railroads--Canada.
  - Letter to Bessie Frank Anathan ("My Dear Bess"), 1908 Sep. 20; 1.0 item; 1 page. 8 x 10-1/4.; Jacobs, Norman Leonard, 1885-
    In the field. Thanks for a "splendid cake," for which "the boys all toasted you as the best cook in Pittsburg."
  - Letter to Bessie Frank Anathan ("Dear Sis"), 1908 Oct. 4; 1.0 item; 4 pages. 8 x 10.; Jacobs, Norman Leonard, 1885-
    Winnipeg. Discusses classes, sister's wedding, the railroad industry and the Canadian election.
    Anathan, Bessie Frank, 1885-1976 -- Correspondence; Collie, Ruth, 1888-1936; Railroads--Canada.
  - Letter to Bessie Frank Anathan ("Dear Old Bettsie"), 1908 Nov. 14; 1.0 item; 4 pages. 8-1/4 x 10-3/4. Grand Trunk Pacific Railway letterhead.; Jacobs, Norman Leonard, 1885-
    "Residency 49," Edmonton. Describes company's work with pride. Mentions Helen, to whom he also writes.
  - Letter to Bessie Frank Anathan ("Dear Bess"), 1908 Dec.; 1.0 item; 2 pages. 6-1/4 x 10-1/4.; Jacobs, Norman Leonard, 1885-
    Alberta. Nearing the end of work, wishes for the new year.
    Date based on references to the GTP crossing the Battle River (the bridge was completed 10 Dec. 1908).
  - Letter to Bessie Frank Anathan ("Dear Bess"), 1910 Oct. 8; 1.0 item; 8 pages. 8 x 10-1/4. Bibliophile Press letterhead.; Jacobs, Norman Leonard, 1885-
    London. Discusses Imperial policy, impressions of unfriendly, crowded island. In the U.K. since March, taking a post-graduate course at the Imperial College of Science and Technology. Plans to return to Pittsburgh. Mentions "the right side of my face is a little the worse for wear from dynamite." Asks to verify news (Mrs. E. Rauch's death and Helen Kaufman's marriage to Edgar--an "impossibility" and "national calamity," respectively).
    Anathan, Bessie Frank, 1885-1976 -- Correspondence; Anecdotes.; Jews--Pennsylvania--Pittsburgh.; London (England) -- Description and travel.; Railroads--England.
  - Letter to Bessie Frank Anathan ("Dear Bess"), 1910 Dec. 15; 1.0 item; 4 pages. 8 x 10-1/4. Bibliophile Press letterhead.; Jacobs, Norman Leonard, 1885-
    London. Death of Uncle Abe's mother, his father "at death's door."
    Anathan, Bessie Frank, 1885-1976 -- Correspondence; Anecdotes.; London (England) -- Description and travel.
  - Letter to Bessie Frank Anathan, undated; 1.0 item; 2 pages. 5-1/2 x 8-3/4.; Jacobs, Norman Leonard, 1885-
    Fragment. Pages 2 and 3. Discusses horses, sleigh dogs, news from home ("one of your little tiffs" with Helen).
    Anathan, Bessie Frank, 1885-1976 -- Correspondence; Frontier and pioneer life -- Canada.
  - Letter to Bessie Frank Anathan, undated; 1.0 item; 1 page. 8 x 10-1/4.; Jacobs, Norman Leonard, 1885-
    Fragment. Page 4. Night sounds in the wilderness.
  - Diary of a Tenderfoot, 1905-1906; 1.0 item; 28 pages. 8 x 10-1/2. Some pages written on Grand Trunk Pacific Railway letterhead.; Jacobs, Norman Leonard, 1885-
    Rail travel to Toronto, life in Winnipeg and in the field. Descriptions of camp life, wildlife, terrain and weather.
    Each of five parts appears to have been written on the same day, or at least during the same general period. Part 1 (pp. 1-4) describes the train to Toronto. Part 2 (pp. 5-10) describes winter in Winnipeg. Part 3 (pp. 11-16) was written on May 1 (p. 14) in the vicinity of Lipton and makes reference to April activities. Part 4 (pp. 17-22) consists of anecdotes of camp life and is incomplete. Part 5 (pp. 23-28) is dated June, on the strength of a reference to the "month of strawberries" (p. 27). The 1905-1906 dates assigned to the material correspond to Jacobs's arrival in Winnipeg and his first foray into the field, as detailed in correspondence.
    Descriptions of the difficulty finding water and nocturnal noises appear on page 22 (breaking off mid-sentence), and are then duplicated on page 23. This may indicate that some pages were intended as drafts or that a sufficient period passed between the first passage and the second that Jacobs forgot having written it or that the pages were intended to be parts of different works. (The varying titles assigned to different pages--"The Diary of a Tenderfoot," "A Tenderfoot's Notes," "The Notebook"--provide some meager support for the latter theory, though in those cases the pages are noted as a continuation of an ongoing work.)
    Anecdotes.; Diaries.; Frontier and pioneer life -- Canada.; Railroads--Canada.; Winnipeg (Man.)--Social life and customs--20th century.
  - Photographs, undated; 14.0 items; 14 loose photographs, enclosed in photo sleeves.; Jacobs, Norman Leonard, 1885-
    Photographs of, or taken by, Norman Jacobs. See Series II for individual descriptions.
    Jacobs, Norman Leonard, 1885- -- Pictorial works; Photographs.
- Series II. Graphic Materials, 1906 - 1908; 1.0 box 2 photobooks (315 photographs)
  - "The National Transcontinental Division of the East: District T, Northern Ontario", 1906; 1.0 item
    Photographs.; Railroads--Canada.
  - "The Plains Eastern Slope", 1906; 1.0 Photograph(s)
    Landscapes--Canada.; Photographs.
  - "McLead River Eastern Slope", 1906; 1.0 Photograph(s)
  - "The Eastern Slopes Clearing R.W.", 1906; 1.0 Photograph(s)
  - "In the Muskeg Country Eastern Slopes", 1906; 1.0 Photograph(s)
  - "Muskeg and Swamp - Eastern Slope", 1906; 1.0 Photograph(s)
  - "Muskeg and Swamp - Eastern Slope", 1906; 1.0 Photograph(s)
  - "Pack Potties in Camp", 1906; 1.0 Photograph(s)
  - "Pack Potties in Camp", 1906; 1.0 Photograph(s)
  - "Loading up for the yellowhead", 1906; 1.0 Photograph(s)
  - "The Last Knot", 1906; 1.0 Photograph(s)
  - "The Head of the Column", 1906; 1.0 Photograph(s)
  - "Hitting the Trail", 1906; 1.0 Photograph(s)
  - "A Bunch of Pack Ponies", 1906; 1.0 Photograph(s)
  - "The Yellowhead Pack Train Leaving Residency 49 for Their 400 Mile Journey", 1906; 1.0 Photograph(s)
  - "In The Beuler Country", 1906; 1.0 Photograph(s)
  - "Towards the Pass", 1906; 1.0 Photograph(s)
    Landscapes--Canada.; Photographs.; Railroads--Canada.
  - "Towards the Pass", 1906; 1.0 Photograph(s)
  - "A Right of Way Camp", 1906; 1.0 Photograph(s)
    Frontier and pioneer life -- Canada.; Photographs.; Railroads--Canada.
  - "Half Breed Packers", 1906; 1.0 Photograph(s)
  - "The Sun Dance", 1906; 1.0 Photograph(s)
    Indians of North America--Rites and ceremonies; Photographs.
  - "The Sun Dance", 1906; 1.0 Photograph(s)
  - "Grand Forks the Yellowhead", 1906; 1.0 Photograph(s)
  - "A Glimpse of the Fraser", 1906; 1.0 Photograph(s)
  - "Along the Fraser", 1906; 1.0 Photograph(s)
  - "Along the Fraser", 1906; 1.0 Photograph(s)
  - "Mount Robson From the Fraser", 1906; 1.0 Photograph(s)
  - "The Caraboo Range", 1906; 1.0 Photograph(s)
  - "At Tete Jaune Cache, Old Joe", 1906; 1.0 Photograph(s)
    Indians of North America--Material culture--Canada.; Photographs.
  - "Tete Jaune Cache, Marie of the High Country", 1906; 1.0 Photograph(s)
  - "The Bear River", 1906; 1.0 Photograph(s)
  - "The Athabasca", 1906; 1.0 Photograph(s)
  - "At the Foot of the Yellowhead", 1906; 1.0 Photograph(s)
  - "In the Heart of the Yellowhead", 1906; 1.0 Photograph(s)
  - "In the Heart of the Yellowhead", 1906; 1.0 Photograph(s)
  - "On the Roof of the Dominion", 1906; 1.0 Photograph(s)
  - "Mt. Robson", 1906; 1.0 Photograph(s)
  - "Mt. Robson: The Summit (Taken a year and a half before the scaling)", 1906; 1.0 Photograph(s)
  - "In the Heart of the Yellowhead", 1906; 1.0 Photograph(s)
  - "In the Heart of the Yellowhead", 1906; 1.0 Photograph(s)
  - "In the Heart of the Yellowhead", 1906; 1.0 Photograph(s)
  - "In the Heart of the Yellowhead", 1906; 1.0 Photograph(s)
  - "In the Heart of Yellowhead", 1906; 1.0 Photograph(s)
  - "P.C.1204R", 1906; 1.0 Photograph(s)
    Frontier and pioneer life -- Canada.; Photographs.
  - "P.C.1202R", 1906; 1.0 Photograph(s)